I work at a big tech company. I jokingly
say it's a fruit company.
>> Hints hints.
>> I came from Korea. I didn't study here.
I was very desperate to get a job. It
was very difficult times. I felt a lot.
Honestly, I cannot believe that I'm
here. What's [music] more important than
learning the language was
>> Can you introduce yourself?
>> My name is Chae Woo Hyung in Korean and
I go by the English name Shawn. I'm an
engineer. I work at a big tech company.
I jokingly say it's a fruit company.
>> Hints hints.
>> [laughter]
>> I live here in United States in Bay
Area. I've been here with my family for
almost 13 years.
>> Can you tell me a little bit more about
your job? Like your day-to-day
responsibilities or like what you're in
charge of there?
>> make iPhone apps. I work in front of
computer and coding. These days I use AI
a lot.
>> Have you been doing this the whole time,
like the 13 years you've been in the US?
>> Yes. I got a job as a software engineer
back in Korea, too. And I always wanted
to move here in Silicon Valley because
this is like a center of the all the
tech industry. I was like desperately
looking for opportunity here for quite a
while, like one or two years. I tried
many things. I contacted many people on
Twitter. I mean, I have talked to people
who work in here in Silicon Valley. I
made some connections. Also, back in I
think 2011, I was traveling here in Bay
Area and I filmed a YouTube video. I
made a video about Bay Area and tech
industry and I interviewed many people
like we are doing right now
who is working [clears throat] in tech
industry and I made some connection
there. So yeah, that was a start. Back
in Korea, I went to like a tech
conference where many tech industry
people came and I made a business card
and I gave it to many people and I told
everyone that I'm looking for a job in
Silicon Valley and one of them knew
someone who founded a company here, so
he connected me to the founder. So,
that's [music] how I got the job.
>> Wow, that's really cool. So, a lot of
word of mouth, networking, just putting
yourself out there.
>> Yeah, that was important putting myself
out there. I don't believe in career
advice, but I believe people get
inspiration from other people's stories.
>> Mhm.
>> What I want to tell other people who
also want to maybe get a job in the
United States or work in tech industry,
just put yourself out there and don't be
afraid. It's okay if it doesn't work,
you know, you don't lose anything. I
think it started from my love for United
States actually. When I was a kid, I
have some relatives who live in here in
California, Sacramento, and I have
visited them few times back in '90s. It
dates me, but
I fell in love with this California
life. The sun is shining all the time
and to like a younger self, it would
look like a dream like life here. So, I
wanted to move to United States and I
dreamed about studying here for high
school and college. That didn't work
out, but I still had that dream in my
mind. So, after getting a job in Korea,
I started looking for opportunities
here. When I was in high school, I like
drawing. I like drawing cartoons and
comics.
>> Mhm.
>> And being an animator or cartoonist was
my dream. I also wanted to put my work
out there. Back then, the internet was
starting. Again,
>> Mhm.
>> long time ago.
>> [laughter]
>> So, I wanted to make my own website to
put my art online. That's how how I
started programming and later I fell in
love with technology. I love making
computers like you could like build your
own computers back then. That was the
first computer I bought, which was a
MacBook
>> Mhm.
>> made by Apple. Back then, no one was
using MacBooks around me, so I fell in
love with it how intuitive the user
interface is, things like that. So, I
was like telling everyone to how good
this device is.
>> That's really cool how your passion,
your life experience, like traveling to
California, all of that kind of led you
here. That's wild.
>> I admire Steve Jobs.
>> [laughter]
>> He's one of my heroes. He made a speech
in Stanford before he died, and he was
talking about connecting dots. If you
look back your life, everything is just
connecting dots. And you don't know when
things are happening, but if look back
later, everything you experienced lead
to where you are right now. So, I
believe that.
>> Yeah, I think like you're living proof
of that.
>> [laughter]
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
Before, like you said, you had this kind
of American dream, and now you're living
here. When you first moved here, was it
challenging, or was it kind of
everything you dreamed of? Were there
hardships?
>> Yeah, there was challenges, for sure.
But for me, it was like my dream coming
true. But I think it was more
challenging for my wife, Wonji. I asked
her to come here with me after we got
married. But yeah, there was some
challenges, culture shock, things like
that. First thing I remember, right
after I came to US, was that my uncle
was picking me up from the airport, and
he brought me to Taco Bell. It's a
franchise, you know, fast food place.
And after eating, back in Korea, I'm
very used to recycle everything, like
separate everything, right? But he was
just dump everything in a one bucket or
one trash can.
>> [laughter]
>> I was very shocked. That was like first
culture shock that I experienced.
>> That's so funny. That's very true. Korea
takes like the sorting, recycling very
seriously. Here, it's like everything
goes in one bin.
>> Yeah. If you're in California, people
are better in recycling and composting,
but still, it's very different from
Korea.
>> Not in Michigan.
>> [laughter]
>> All in one bin.
>> But there are very positive side of
American culture. It's very diverse
culture here. So, many races, many
different people. So, people are very
used to being careful about
stereotyping, not not stereotyping of
for other people, right? And that's one
of the reasons I wanted to move to
America.
>> Even just coming back here this time, we
were walking down the street and we
heard so many different languages around
us. And I was like, "Wow, it really is
so global." It's just super
international.
>> Yeah, especially here in Bay Area, there
are a lot of different culture are
mixing.
>> Yeah, that is really cool. I think you
get to experience a lot of different
cultures in one place.
>> And one good thing about that is that
they have really great food from all
around the world. We have great Asian
food, even Korean food.
>> Mhm. We've been eating well here.
>> [laughter]
>> Too well, probably.
How about language when you first moved
here? Did you face any language barriers
or how was your English at the time?
>> I think I was lucky. I was exposed to
English since I was a kid. My dad
traveled to United States many times. He
brought some VHS tapes again.
A long time ago.
Maybe [laughter] some of the viewers
[snorts] don't know what it is. So, he
brought like a Disney video tapes. I
watched a lot of them with Korean
subtitle. That's how I got exposed to
English from early ages. Because of
that, I built like confidence in
English. And after moved here, even
though I don't speak perfect English
with perfect grammar, I was not afraid
of speaking to people and I was actually
enjoying it, enjoying to meeting new
people, speaking to people in from
different culture. And that confidence
was built up. And I think that helped a
lot. I think that's very important when
you learn a language to have a
confidence and just try it out, you
know? I think the other one is like a
social media. In the beginning
[clears throat]
time of Twitter, there was something
called Twitter up. I made a made a with
foreign people who live in Seoul and we
had like offsite or in-person meetings
and made friends with them. I learned a
lot of English from them, too. I ended
up creating like a startup company with
people I met at Twitter.
>> Ah, well, that's so interesting. I think
a lot of people are always asking and
they're always curious about like how to
meet foreign friends in Korea to
practice their English. And I always
just tell them to like go to Itaewon.
Definitely, you can use a platform. I
think now it's a lot easier with social
media to make friends that way.
>> I think I would say it's better if you
find friends who speaks English, who has
common interest with you. So, being in a
like a for example, movie community or I
don't know, some sports community,
that'll be great because you have other
stuff that you can connect with other
than the language. So, I think to me,
living here in United States, what's
more important than learning the
language was to learn in the culture, I
think. That's what I felt. If you think
about some foreign people who's in who
living in Seoul, you have to live in
Korea for a long time,
you feel more familiar with them if they
understand the culture and they respect
the culture. Like, for example, Korean
drinking culture, you know?
>> [laughter]
>> I know nothing about that.
>> If someone is very good at the culture
and they try to respect it and their
friends will like it more and I think if
you live in different country like us,
you try to learn the culture and what's
offending to the people, what makes them
happy.
>> Mhm.
>> And learning those things are more
important, I think, than learning
language perfectly.
>> That's a good point. It goes deeper than
just learning the grammar, learning the
vocab. You have to understand the
culture. Huge part of it.
When you talk to other people here and
especially like, you know, 13 years ago
when you first got here, if your English
wasn't at the level it is now. Now
you're really great. But, you know, when
you first moved here and were engaging
in conversation with other people, were
they usually pretty friendly? A lot of
people worry like, "Oh, I'm like slow
when I talk." Or if I don't say
something right, like, "Will people
understand me?" Were people like pretty
good about that when you engage in
conversation?
>> Yeah, I think we are also pretty lucky
because we met a lot of people who
became our friends who are very nice to
us and they are very understanding of
our English not being perfect.
>> Mhm.
>> And we were involved in like a American
church and we made great friends there
and think that helped us a lot in the
beginning to be used to speaking to
American people and like you said, they
are very understanding. So, it made us
to not be afraid of of speaking more.
>> That makes me really happy cuz I always
think it does take a lot of confidence
and it is scary speaking in a different
language. But, I think sometimes the
biggest critic is yourself. Other people
won't judge you, but maybe we judge
ourselves too harshly. So,
>> You don't need to do that.
>> Yeah. And I think finding a great
community can also probably be a great
way to practice.
>> And I also what I learned from working
here, working is also a little bit
different than just making friends,
right?
>> Mhm.
>> At first I was not confident about work
because it's again, it's different. You
have to use professional terms. But,
what I learned was that even people who
were born and raised here, some people
don't speak perfect I mean, they don't
speak well.
>> 100%
>> [laughter]
>> And even like me, when I speak Korean, I
was not a person who speaks very well.
Even especially like public speaking.
Sometimes when I speak Korean, I feel
like, "Why can't I speak well?"
>> [laughter]
>> Takes long time to think about a word
and I think it's same when I speak in
English. So, that thought made me more
confidence. Like, I think one benefit of
being a non-native speaker is that you
use easier word
>> Mhm.
>> and you speak slowly. So, other people
understand you better, I think.
>> That's a great perspective. I never
thought of it like that, but that's very
true.
>> Yeah, and uh you also prepare a lot
because you're not perfect. You write
down, you memorize it, and speak it, so
you don't use a lot of filler words. So,
that's easier for people who listening.
>> Mhm.
>> I think there's some benefit of that.
>> That's true. Cuz sometimes even I have a
hard time understanding other people if
they speak really fast. I'm like, "Wait,
what?"
>> [laughter]
>> So, that's a really good point.
>> Mhm.
>> I know you said you watched Disney. Do
you have a specific movie you remember
watching at that time that kind of made
you curious about English or
>> Yeah, I learned a lot of my English from
movies and TV shows. I also watched a
lot of Friends, the American TV show,
and I watched many times the whole
season. BTS also learned English from
Friends.
>> [laughter]
>> And also other TV shows like Lost or 24,
which are also popular in Korea. What I
have been trying to learn English was to
immerse myself in English-speaking
environment. I intentionally don't turn
on Korean subtitle. I always turn on
English subtitle though. Sometimes I
cannot understand it, I can read it,
right? I also read books in English,
which doesn't help my reading habit. I
don't I don't read a lot of books.
But I also read books that I'm
interested in
that I know well. I I read a lot about
like tech industry, and it's easier to
digest for me.
>> Working at a big company like this, like
you said, the English is very different.
It's very professional. And especially
in the tech industry, they use a lot of
like tech jargon. Was that really
challenging at first?
>> Yes, at first it was challenging, but I
listened to a lot of podcasts, too. Tech
tech industry podcast and that helped me
a lot to getting familiar with the the
jargons or some terms like professional
terms and also listening to other people
at work in meetings that helped a lot
too.
>> Mhm.
>> When I heard some phrase that I've never
or expressions that I've never heard of,
I remember that, try to use that in the
similar situation in the future.
So yeah, I learned from co-workers and
friends a lot too.
>> That's really awesome. I love how
proactive you are about learning
English. That's really great. Your whole
journey of learning English is actually
very inspirational.
>> But I don't feel like I I try hard to
learn English. I just enjoy it. I like
speaking in English and I think
essentially I like learning about new
culture, meeting new people who grew up
in different environment.
>> Mhm.
>> And that curiosity helped me a lot to
kind of learning English without trying
too much.
>> That's great. I think if you can find a
way that you enjoy it, that's the best
way to do it.
So now you're working at your dream job.
>> Yes.
>> Can you kind of tell me how you achieved
that especially since it's such a
competitive market?
>> Honestly, I cannot believe that I'm
here. There's a thing called imposter
syndrome. I had that when I first get my
dream job in a big tech company because
I came from Korea. I didn't study here.
I didn't graduate here. It was hard to
compete with other people who who
graduated in in a more famous school.
And for my age, usually my peers are
like younger than me because I came here
in a older age, right? But I I still
love that I'm [snorts] I'm working here.
And because of I studied in the older
age, I have some other different
experience compared to other like
younger people. That's an advantage too.
>> Do you have like a specific or practical
action item.
>> Start from the company that you don't
really like.
>> [laughter]
>> And make that as an as a learning
experience. And if you think you're
ready, you can try a company you like.
Or you can just try to interview with
the company you like even if you fail.
And I think it also helps you have a
friend of who work in tech industry, you
can ask them to do like a mock interview
with them. I don't think I can even
count. There was like maybe around like
40, 50.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. It was very difficult times. I
failed a lot. But as that accumulates,
you fail less. You can see that. You can
see the progress.
>> I really like respect you for that
because I'm sure like that must be so
discouraging. You know, you start
questioning yourself and am I good
enough? Am I on the right path? Can I do
this? But like you pushed through all
that and you've landed your dream job.
So and it's well deserved. Like that's
really cool.
>> But there was also like another reason
that I was very desperate to get a job
like a visa.
>> Mhm.
>> If I didn't get a job here, I had to go
back to Korea.
>> [laughter]
>> That's another level of pressure then.
>> Yeah, pressure. Yeah. Also, recently
because I have been working here for a
while, I got an opportunity to interview
other people to hire to my team. And if
you be in the other side of the
interview, that helps tremendously too.
>> Yeah, I bet.
>> You know what kind of person you like to
hire. So if you flip that, if you want
to get hired by someone, you can use
that knowledge.
>> What kind of person do you like to hire?
>> [laughter]
>> Um maybe it's different every people,
but for me, if you make me laugh during
the interview, you have a higher chance
to get hired.
>> [laughter]
>> I I made you laugh maybe once, right?
Can I get a job?
>> [laughter]
>> That means like not making jokes or
anything, but try to be comfortable with
the interviewer and talk about something
that's not related to the interview,
like maybe you can find common interest
with the person. I think that made both
of them relaxed. So, that's kind of my
practical tip for interviews. Recently,
I interviewed someone and it was very
obvious they're using AI to answer the
questions. It sounded very like AI.
Every sentence they said like, "Oh, in
summary, this is this."
>> [laughter]
>> Don't do that.
>> Keep it, yeah, authentic, genuine.
>> Mhm.
>> Can you tell me a little bit about the
working environment where you are? Maybe
the company culture, what do you do to
survive there?
>> So, I think American culture, especially
in the tech industry, uh it's very
important to show what you did, your
result. And I'm a kind of shy person, so
I'm not used to that, too, but I learned
that it's important. So, like if you
have opportunity to show what you did to
some leaders of your organization, find
those opportunities and do that. But, I
also think it's same in Korean culture
and American culture, but if you try too
hard to kind of promote yourself, other
people don't like it.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> But, if you have opportunity and if you
can keep the balance of being humble and
show yourself more, you have to catch
that opportunity and do that.
>> Mhm. Just there's a line, right? You got
to be careful of the line.
>> There's a line.
>> [laughter]
>> Absolutely.
>> Just my own curiosity. I always see like
all the TikTok videos and stuff of the
big tech companies. Day in the life of
someone working at this big company, and
they always show like all the breakfast
buffets, all the lunch buffets. Is it
really like that? What are some of the
perks you get to enjoy?
>> Perks.
The companies I have worked at, they had
catered free lunch. At my current
company, I I to still pay for the food
from our cafeteria. We didn't have a lot
of layoffs recently where other
companies had a lot of layoffs. So,
being frugal like that, you know, I
think it's positive.
>> Yeah, you're like, "I'll pay for my
lunch."
>> [laughter]
>> I pay for my lunch. Don't fire me.
>> That's so funny. That makes sense. Are
you currently working on any projects or
do you have any future goals?
>> I cannot talk about my work stuff, but
personally, I I really like movies. And
one of the goals this year was to write
more movie reviews. So, I started an
account on Threads. It's called Bay
Movie Chat.
>> Bay Movie Chat. Okay.
>> I write movie reviews in Korean. So, I
connect with movie fans in Korea.
>> Wow.
>> It's very small. I don't have a lot of
followers. It's fun
>> Mhm.
>> to get connected with other people who
have same interest.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh yeah, that's what I'm trying to do
this year.
>> What's a movie you've watched recently
that you recommend?
>> Recently, I watched Project Hail Mary. I
don't know if you have watched it.
>> Yes, loved it.
>> You loved it? Okay.
>> Loved it.
>> Mhm.
>> I
>> You didn't love it. [laughter]
>> I had too much expectations, so I didn't
love it as much as other people, but I
enjoyed it. I enjoyed watching it. The
one movie I liked recently was 28 Years
Later. It's like a horror movie, but I'm
a horror movie fan, so I really like
that movie.
>> I like horror, but I haven't watched it.
I'm like this half the time, but I enjoy
it. I know it's a series, right? There's
a couple of them.
>> Yeah, the latest one is called The Bone
Temple.
>> Uh-huh.
>> So, it's really great movie.
>> I'll have to watch it. I have to start
from number one and watch them, maybe.
>> You don't have to watch everything to
enjoy this movie, but it's better if you
watch
>> Okay. I'll do that. Thank you so much
for letting me interview you today and
for sharing your story with us.
>> Thank you so much. I really enjoyed this
chat.
>> I would love to do this again in the
future, so hopefully see you again back
here. Thank you so much for watching and
see you next time. Bye.
>> Bye.